<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overview on MGX metagenome analysis platform</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overview on MGX metagenome analysis platform</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 14:38:10 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 12:07:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/about/</guid>
      <description>About The characterization of microbial communities based on sequencing and analysis of their genetic information has become a popular approach also referred to as metagenomics; in particular, the recent advances in sequencing technologies have enabled researchers to study even the most complex communities.&#xA;Metagenome analysis, the assignment of sequences to taxonomic and functional entities, however, remains a tedious task: large amounts of data need to be processed. There are a number of approaches addressing particular aspects, but scientific questions are often too specific to be answered by a general-purpose method.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install MGX</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/install-mgx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/install-mgx/</guid>
      <description>Needed prerequisites, Java JDK Version 17, Supported operating systems and obtaining MGX.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basics</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 16:29:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/basics/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents Obtaining a Project&#xA;MGX Roles&#xA;Metadata&#xA;Connecting to Server&#xA;Obtaining a MGX project Currently, there is no way to automatically create new MGX projects. If you would like to analyze your metagenome or metatranscriptome data with MGX, please send a mail to the MGX team, which can be contacted at:&#xA;mgx@computational.bio.uni-giessen.de.&#xA;MGX projects and users are managed by the General Project Management System (GPMS) developed at CeBiTec (Bielefeld University), which provides Single Sign-On (SSO) for all our applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 11:30:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/projects/</guid>
      <description>Handling a Project by creating a new habitat, creating new samples and DNA extracts and how to import sequence data</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 13:50:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/analysis/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents Quality&#xA;Selecting a analysis pipeline&#xA;Job Monitoring&#xA;Quality Control Select a sequencing run object, the Quality Control component can be opened from its menubar icon (red circle).&#xA;Quality control reports generated within MGX should be inspected before proceding with data analysis.&#xA;MGX currently offers three types of QC reports:&#xA;Distribution of GC content sequence length nucleotide distribution within the DNA sequences Those can be used to evaluate overall sequence data quality and check for possible signs of contamination.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assembly</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 14:38:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/assembly/</guid>
      <description>Assembling a metagenome or metatranscriptome Since MGX 2.0, we support the assembly and analysis of both metagenomes and metatranscriptomes; for this, we provide workflows targeting QC, (co-)assembly, gene prediction, taxonomic binning, completeness assessment, and abundance quantification.&#xA;For metatranscriptomes, an additional step is implemented for the removal of ribosomal RNA sequences prior to the assembly, and binning is not performed.&#xA;To create an assembly, select all sequencing runs that should be co-assembled within the Project Explorer window and select the Assemble entry from the context menu.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Whisper</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whisper is a minimal documentation theme built for Hugo. The design &amp;amp; functionality is intentionally minimal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Costum Pipelines</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/costum_pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 13:22:16 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/costum_pipelines/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents General&#xA;Getting started&#xA;Workflow requirements&#xA;Annotating metagenome sequences&#xA;Creating hierarchical attributes&#xA;General All offered analysis tools provided by the MGX platform are implemented as workflows for the Conveyor Linke et al.,2011 workflow engine developed by B. Linke. Within Conveyor, tools are provided as so-called nodes, which resemble individual processing steps and which are used to implement novel analysis methods by simply arranging and connecting them into a larger workflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 12:57:39 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/references/</guid>
      <description>Altschul et al., 1990 Altschul, S. F., Gish, W., Miller, W., Myers, E. W., and Lipman, D. J. (1990).Basic local alignment search tool. Journal of molecular biology, 215(3):403–410. Hughes et al., 2002 Hughes, J. B., Hellmann, J. J., Ricketts, T. H., and Bohannan, B. J. (2002). Counting the uncountable: Statistical approaches to estimating microbial diversity. Applied and environmental microbiology, 68(1):448. Langmead and Salzberg, 2012 Langmead, B. and Salzberg, S. L.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Theme</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/install-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/install-theme/</guid>
      <description>Create a new Hugo site hugo new site mynewsite This will create a fresh Hugo site in the folder mynewsite.&#xA;Install theme Copy or git clone this theme into the sites themes folder mynewsite/themes&#xA;Install with Git cd mynewsite cd themes git clone https://github.com/jugglerx/hugo-whisper-theme.git Install from .zip file You can download the .zip file located here https://github.com/JugglerX/hugo-whisper-theme/archive/master.zip.&#xA;Extract the downloaded .zip inside the themes folder. Rename the extracted folder from hugo-whisper-theme-master -&amp;gt; hugo-whisper-theme.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Specimen</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/specimen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/specimen/</guid>
      <description>Markdown Test Page Headings Paragraphs Blockquotes Lists Horizontal rule Table Code Inline elements Headings Heading one Sint sit cillum pariatur eiusmod nulla pariatur ipsum. Sit laborum anim qui mollit tempor pariatur nisi minim dolor. Aliquip et adipisicing sit sit fugiat commodo id sunt. Nostrud enim ad commodo incididunt cupidatat in ullamco ullamco Lorem cupidatat velit enim et Lorem.&#xA;Heading two Aute officia nulla deserunt do deserunt cillum velit magna. Officia veniam culpa anim minim dolore labore pariatur voluptate id ad est duis quis velit dolor pariatur enim.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/configure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/configure/</guid>
      <description>Syntax highlighting and menus can be configured via &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
